<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paper-Journal | Rohit Girdhar</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/publication-type/paper-journal/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/publication-type/paper-journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Paper-Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu_9c1485188d0073ca.png</url>
      <title>Paper-Journal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication-type/paper-journal/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diffusion Autoencoders are Scalable Image Tokenizers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2025_dito/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2025_dito/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tokenizing images into compact visual representations is a key step in learning efficient and high-quality image generative models. We present a simple diffusion tokenizer (DiTo) that learns compact visual representations for image generation models. Our key insight is that a single learning objective, diffusion L2 loss, can be used for training scalable image tokenizers. Since diffusion is already widely used for image generation, our insight greatly simplifies training such tokenizers. In contrast, current state-of-the-art tokenizers rely on an empirically found combination of heuristics and losses, thus requiring a complex training recipe that relies on non-trivially balancing different losses and pretrained supervised models. We show design decisions, along with theoretical grounding, that enable us to scale DiTo for learning competitive image representations. Our results show that DiTo is a simpler, scalable, and self-supervised alternative to the current state-of-the-art image tokenizer which is supervised. DiTo achieves competitive or better quality than state-of-the-art in image reconstruction and downstream image generation tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LLMs can see and hear without any training</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2025_mils/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2025_mils/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We present MILS: Multimodal Iterative LLM Solver, a surprisingly simple, training-free approach, to imbue multimodal capabilities into your favorite LLM. Leveraging their innate ability to perform multi-step reasoning, MILS prompts the LLM to generate candidate outputs, each of which are scored and fed back iteratively, eventually generating a solution to the task. This enables various applications that typically require training specialized models on task-specific data. In particular, we establish a new state-of-the-art on emergent zero-shot image, video and audio captioning. MILS seamlessly applies to media generation as well, discovering prompt rewrites to improve text-to-image generation, and even edit prompts for style transfer! Finally, being a gradient-free optimization approach, MILS can invert multimodal embeddings into text, enabling applications like cross-modal arithmetic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MotiF: Making Text Count in Image Animation with Motion Focal Loss</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2024_motif/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2024_motif/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Text-Image-to-Video (TI2V) generation aims to generate a video from an image following a text description, which is also referred to as text-guided image animation. Most existing methods struggle to generate videos that align well with the text prompts, particularly when motion is specified. To overcome this limitation, we introduce MotiF, a simple yet effective approach that directs the model&amp;rsquo;s learning to the regions with more motion, thereby improving the text alignment and motion generation. We use optical flow to generate a motion heatmap and weight the loss according to the intensity of the motion. This modified objective leads to noticeable improvements and complements existing methods that utilize motion priors as model inputs. Additionally, due to the lack of a diverse benchmark for evaluating TI2V generation, we propose TI2V Bench, a dataset consists of 320 image-text pairs for robust evaluation. We present a human evaluation protocol that asks the annotators to select an overall preference between two videos followed by their justifications. Through a comprehensive evaluation on TI2V Bench, MotiF outperforms nine open-sourced models, achieving an average preference of 72%. The TI2V Bench is released in &lt;a href=&#34;https://wang-sj16.github.io/motif/&#34;&gt;this https URL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Gen: A Cast of Media Foundation Models</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2024_moviegen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2024_moviegen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We present Movie Gen, a cast of foundation models that generates high-quality, 1080p HD videos with different aspect ratios and synchronized audio. We also show additional capabilities such as precise instruction-based video editing and generation of personalized videos based on a user&amp;rsquo;s image. Our models set a new state-of-the-art on multiple tasks: text-to-video synthesis, video personalization, video editing, video-to-audio generation, and text-to-audio generation. Our largest video generation model is a 30B parameter transformer trained with a maximum context length of 73K video tokens, corresponding to a generated video of 16 seconds at 16 frames-per-second. We show multiple technical innovations and simplifications on the architecture, latent spaces, training objectives and recipes, data curation, evaluation protocols, parallelization techniques, and inference optimizations that allow us to reap the benefits of scaling pre-training data, model size, and training compute for training large scale media generation models. We hope this paper helps the research community to accelerate progress and innovation in media generation models. All videos from this paper are available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL86eLlsPNfyi27GSizYjinpYxp7gEl5K8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this https URL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Llama 3 Herd of Models</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2024_llama3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2024_llama3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Modern artificial intelligence (AI) systems are powered by foundation models. This paper presents a new set of foundation models, called Llama 3. It is a herd of language models that natively support multilinguality, coding, reasoning, and tool usage. Our largest model is a dense Transformer with 405B parameters and a context window of up to 128K tokens. This paper presents an extensive empirical evaluation of Llama 3. We find that Llama 3 delivers comparable quality to leading language models such as GPT-4 on a plethora of tasks. We publicly release Llama 3, including pre-trained and post-trained versions of the 405B parameter language model and our Llama Guard 3 model for input and output safety. The paper also presents the results of experiments in which we integrate image, video, and speech capabilities into Llama 3 via a compositional approach. We observe this approach performs competitively with the state-of-the-art on image, video, and speech recognition tasks. The resulting models are not yet being broadly released as they are still under development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motion-Conditioned Image Animation for Video Editing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2023_moca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2023_moca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We introduce MoCA, a Motion-Conditioned Image Animation approach for video editing. It leverages a simple decomposition of the video editing problem into image editing followed by motion-conditioned image animation. Furthermore, given the lack of robust evaluation datasets for video editing, we introduce a new benchmark that measures edit capability across a wide variety of tasks, such as object replacement, background changes, style changes, and motion edits. We present a comprehensive human evaluation of the latest video editing methods along with MoCA, on our proposed benchmark. MoCA establishes a new state-of-the-art, demonstrating greater human preference win-rate, and outperforming notable recent approaches including Dreamix (63%), MasaCtrl (75%), and Tune-A-Video (72%), with especially significant improvements for motion edits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emu Video: Factorizing Text-to-Video Generation by Explicit Image Conditioning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2023_emuvideo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2023_emuvideo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We present Emu Video, a text-to-video generation model that factorizes the generation into two steps: first generating an image conditioned on the text, and then generating a video conditioned on the text and the generated image. We identify critical design decisions&amp;ndash;adjusted noise schedules for diffusion, and multi-stage training&amp;ndash;that enable us to directly generate high quality and high resolution videos, without requiring a deep cascade of models as in prior work. In human evaluations, our generated videos are strongly preferred in quality compared to all prior work&amp;ndash;81% vs. Google&amp;rsquo;s Imagen Video, 90% vs. Nvidia&amp;rsquo;s PYOCO, and 96% vs. Meta&amp;rsquo;s Make-A-Video. Our model outperforms commercial solutions such as RunwayML&amp;rsquo;s Gen2 and Pika Labs. Finally, our factorizing approach naturally lends itself to animating images based on a user&amp;rsquo;s text prompt, where our generations are preferred 96% over prior work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mask2Former for Video Instance Segmentation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2021_videomask2former/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2021_videomask2former/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We find Mask2Former also achieves state-of-the-art performance on video instance segmentation without modifying the architecture, the loss or even the training pipeline. In this report, we show universal image segmentation architectures trivially generalize to video segmentation by directly predicting 3D segmentation volumes. Specifically, Mask2Former sets a new state-of-the-art of 60.4 AP on YouTubeVIS-2019 and 52.6 AP on YouTubeVIS-2021. We believe Mask2Former is also capable of handling video semantic and panoptic segmentation, given its versatility in image segmentation. We hope this will make state-of-the-art video segmentation research more accessible and bring more attention to designing universal image and video segmentation architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
