<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Selected | Rohit Girdhar</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tag/selected/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tag/selected/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Selected</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu_9c1485188d0073ca.png</url>
      <title>Selected</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tag/selected/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>LLMs can see and hear without any training</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2025_mils/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2025_mils/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We present MILS: Multimodal Iterative LLM Solver, a surprisingly simple, training-free approach, to imbue multimodal capabilities into your favorite LLM. Leveraging their innate ability to perform multi-step reasoning, MILS prompts the LLM to generate candidate outputs, each of which are scored and fed back iteratively, eventually generating a solution to the task. This enables various applications that typically require training specialized models on task-specific data. In particular, we establish a new state-of-the-art on emergent zero-shot image, video and audio captioning. MILS seamlessly applies to media generation as well, discovering prompt rewrites to improve text-to-image generation, and even edit prompts for style transfer! Finally, being a gradient-free optimization approach, MILS can invert multimodal embeddings into text, enabling applications like cross-modal arithmetic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Gen: A Cast of Media Foundation Models</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2024_moviegen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2024_moviegen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We present Movie Gen, a cast of foundation models that generates high-quality, 1080p HD videos with different aspect ratios and synchronized audio. We also show additional capabilities such as precise instruction-based video editing and generation of personalized videos based on a user&amp;rsquo;s image. Our models set a new state-of-the-art on multiple tasks: text-to-video synthesis, video personalization, video editing, video-to-audio generation, and text-to-audio generation. Our largest video generation model is a 30B parameter transformer trained with a maximum context length of 73K video tokens, corresponding to a generated video of 16 seconds at 16 frames-per-second. We show multiple technical innovations and simplifications on the architecture, latent spaces, training objectives and recipes, data curation, evaluation protocols, parallelization techniques, and inference optimizations that allow us to reap the benefits of scaling pre-training data, model size, and training compute for training large scale media generation models. We hope this paper helps the research community to accelerate progress and innovation in media generation models. All videos from this paper are available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL86eLlsPNfyi27GSizYjinpYxp7gEl5K8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this https URL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Llama 3 Herd of Models</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2024_llama3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2024_llama3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Modern artificial intelligence (AI) systems are powered by foundation models. This paper presents a new set of foundation models, called Llama 3. It is a herd of language models that natively support multilinguality, coding, reasoning, and tool usage. Our largest model is a dense Transformer with 405B parameters and a context window of up to 128K tokens. This paper presents an extensive empirical evaluation of Llama 3. We find that Llama 3 delivers comparable quality to leading language models such as GPT-4 on a plethora of tasks. We publicly release Llama 3, including pre-trained and post-trained versions of the 405B parameter language model and our Llama Guard 3 model for input and output safety. The paper also presents the results of experiments in which we integrate image, video, and speech capabilities into Llama 3 via a compositional approach. We observe this approach performs competitively with the state-of-the-art on image, video, and speech recognition tasks. The resulting models are not yet being broadly released as they are still under development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emu Video: Factorizing Text-to-Video Generation by Explicit Image Conditioning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2023_emuvideo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2023_emuvideo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We present Emu Video, a text-to-video generation model that factorizes the generation into two steps: first generating an image conditioned on the text, and then generating a video conditioned on the text and the generated image. We identify critical design decisions&amp;ndash;adjusted noise schedules for diffusion, and multi-stage training&amp;ndash;that enable us to directly generate high quality and high resolution videos, without requiring a deep cascade of models as in prior work. In human evaluations, our generated videos are strongly preferred in quality compared to all prior work&amp;ndash;81% vs. Google&amp;rsquo;s Imagen Video, 90% vs. Nvidia&amp;rsquo;s PYOCO, and 96% vs. Meta&amp;rsquo;s Make-A-Video. Our model outperforms commercial solutions such as RunwayML&amp;rsquo;s Gen2 and Pika Labs. Finally, our factorizing approach naturally lends itself to animating images based on a user&amp;rsquo;s text prompt, where our generations are preferred 96% over prior work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ImageBind: One Embedding Space To Bind Them All</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2023_imagebind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2023_imagebind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We present ImageBind, an approach to learn a joint embedding across six different modalities - images, text, audio, depth, thermal, and IMU data. We show that all combinations of paired data are not necessary to train such a joint embedding, and only image-paired data is sufficient to bind the modalities together. ImageBind can leverage recent large scale vision-language models, and extends their zero-shot capabilities to new modalities just by using their natural pairing with images. It enables novel emergent applications &amp;lsquo;out-of-the-box&amp;rsquo; including cross-modal retrieval, composing modalities with arithmetic, cross-modal detection and generation. The emergent capabilities improve with the strength of the image encoder and we set a new state-of-the-art on emergent zero-shot recognition tasks across modalities, outperforming specialist supervised models. Finally, we show strong few-shot recognition results outperforming prior work, and that ImageBind serves as a new way to evaluate vision models for visual and non-visual tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Video Representations from Large Language Models</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2022_lavila/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2022_lavila/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Video-language embeddings are a promising avenue for injecting semantics into visual representations, but existing methods capture only short-term associations between seconds-long video clips and their accompanying text. We propose HierVL, a novel hierarchical video-language embedding that simultaneously accounts for both long-term and short-term associations. As training data, we take videos accompanied by timestamped text descriptions of human actions, together with a high-level text summary of the activity throughout the long video (as are available in Ego4D). We introduce a hierarchical contrastive training objective that encourages text-visual alignment at both the clip level and video level. While the clip-level constraints use the step-by-step descriptions to capture what is happening in that instant, the video-level constraints use the summary text to capture why it is happening, i.e., the broader context for the activity and the intent of the actor. Our hierarchical scheme yields a clip representation that outperforms its single-level counterpart as well as a long-term video representation that achieves SotA results on tasks requiring long-term video modeling. HierVL successfully transfers to multiple challenging downstream tasks (in EPIC-KITCHENS-100, Charades-Ego, HowTo100M) in both zero-shot and fine-tuned settings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Omnivore: A Single Model for Many Visual Modalities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2022_omnivore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2022_omnivore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prior work has studied different visual modalities in isolation and developed separate architectures for recognition of images, videos, and 3D data. Instead, in this paper, we propose a single model which excels at classifying images, videos, and single-view 3D data using exactly the same model parameters. Our &amp;lsquo;OMNIVORE&amp;rsquo; model leverages the flexibility of transformer-based architectures and is trained jointly on classification tasks from different modalities. OMNIVORE is simple to train, uses off-the-shelf standard datasets, and performs at-par or better than modality-specific models of the same size. A single OMNIVORE model obtains 86.0% on ImageNet, 84.1% on Kinetics, and 67.1% on SUN RGB-D. After finetuning, our models outperform prior work on a variety of vision tasks and generalize across modalities. OMNIVORE&amp;rsquo;s shared visual representation naturally enables cross-modal recognition without access to correspondences between modalities. We hope our results motivate researchers to model visual modalities together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ego4D: Around the World in 3,000 Hours of Egocentric Video</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2022_ego4d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2022_ego4d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We introduce Ego4D, a massive-scale egocentric video dataset and benchmark suite. It offers 3,670 hours of daily-life activity video spanning hundreds of scenarios (household, outdoor, workplace, leisure, etc.) captured by 931 unique camera wearers from 74 worldwide locations and 9 different countries. The approach to collection is designed to uphold rigorous privacy and ethics standards with consenting participants and robust de-identification procedures where relevant. Ego4D dramatically expands the volume of diverse egocentric video footage publicly available to the research community. Portions of the video are accompanied by audio, 3D meshes of the environment, eye gaze, stereo, and/or synchronized videos from multiple egocentric cameras at the same event. Furthermore, we present a host of new benchmark challenges centered around understanding the first-person visual experience in the past (querying an episodic memory), present (analyzing hand-object manipulation, audio-visual conversation, and social interactions), and future (forecasting activities). By publicly sharing this massive annotated dataset and benchmark suite, we aim to push the frontier of first-person perception.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masked-attention Mask Transformer for Universal Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2021_mask2former/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2021_mask2former/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Image segmentation is about grouping pixels with different semantics, e.g., category or instance membership, where each choice of semantics defines a task. While only the semantics of each task differ, current research focuses on designing specialized architectures for each task. We present Masked-attention Mask Transformer (Mask2Former), a new architecture capable of addressing any image segmentation task (panoptic, instance or semantic). Its key components include masked attention, which extracts localized features by constraining cross-attention within predicted mask regions. In addition to reducing the research effort by at least three times, it outperforms the best specialized architectures by a significant margin on four popular datasets. Most notably, Mask2Former sets a new state-of-the-art for panoptic segmentation (57.8 PQ on COCO), instance segmentation (50.1 AP on COCO) and semantic segmentation (57.7 mIoU on ADE20K).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anticipative Video Transformer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2021_avt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2021_avt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We propose Anticipative Video Transformer (AVT), an end-to-end attention-based video modeling architecture that attends to the previously observed video in order to anticipate future actions. We train the model jointly to predict the next action in a video sequence, while also learning frame feature encoders that are predictive of successive future frames&amp;rsquo; features. Compared to existing temporal aggregation strategies, AVT has the advantage of both maintaining the sequential progression of observed actions while still capturing long-range dependencies&amp;ndash;both critical for the anticipation task. Through extensive experiments, we show that AVT obtains the best reported performance on four popular action anticipation benchmarks: EpicKitchens-55, EpicKitchens-100, EGTEA Gaze+, and 50-Salads; and it wins first place in the EpicKitchens-100 CVPR&#39;21 challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CATER: A diagnostic dataset for Compositional Actions and TEmporal Reasoning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2019_cater/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2019_cater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Computer vision has undergone a dramatic revolution in performance, driven in large part through deep features trained on large-scale supervised datasets. However, much of these improvements have focused on static image analysis; video understanding has seen rather modest improvements. Even though new datasets and spatiotemporal models have been proposed, simple frame-by-frame classification methods often still remain competitive. We posit that current video datasets are plagued with implicit biases over scene and object structure that can dwarf variations in temporal structure. In this work, we build a video dataset with fully observable and controllable object and scene bias, and which truly requires spatiotemporal understanding in order to be solved. Our dataset, named CATER, is rendered synthetically using a library of standard 3D objects, and tests the ability to recognize compositions of object movements that require long-term reasoning. As an illustrative example, consider the &amp;ldquo;cups and ball&amp;rdquo; shell game, where a target object (ball) is adversarially passed between container objects (cups) so as to deceive an observer as to its final position. Solving this task requires reasoning about recursive container relations and long-term occlusions. In addition to being a challenging dataset, CATER also provides a plethora of diagnostic tools to analyze modern spatiotemporal video architectures by being completely observable and controllable. Using CATER, we provide insights into some of the most recent state of the art deep video architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Action Transformer Network</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2018_actiontx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2018_actiontx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We introduce the Action Transformer model for recognizing and localizing human actions in video clips. We repurpose a Transformer-style architecture to aggregate features from the spatiotemporal context around the person whose actions we are trying to classify. We show that by using high-resolution, person-specific, class-agnostic queries, the model spontaneously learns to track individual people and to pick up on semantic context from the actions of others. Additionally its attention mechanism learns to emphasize hands and faces, which are often crucial to discriminate an action - all without explicit supervision other than boxes and class labels. We train and test our Action Transformer network on the Atomic Visual Actions (AVA) dataset, outperforming the state-of-the-art by a significant margin using only raw RGB frames as input.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detect-and-Track: Efficient Pose Estimation in Videos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2018_detectandtrack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2018_detectandtrack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper addresses the problem of estimating and tracking human body keypoints in complex, multi-person video. We propose an extremely lightweight yet highly effective approach that builds upon the latest advancements in human detection and video understanding. Our method operates in two-stages: keypoint estimation in frames or short clips, followed by lightweight tracking to generate keypoint predictions linked over the entire video. For frame-level pose estimation we experiment with Mask R-CNN, as well as our own proposed 3D extension of this model, which leverages temporal information over small clips to generate more robust frame predictions. We conduct extensive ablative experiments on the newly released multi-person video pose estimation benchmark, PoseTrack, to validate various design choices of our model. Our approach achieves an accuracy of 55.2% on the validation and 51.8% on the test set using the Multi-Object Tracking Accuracy (MOTA) metric, and achieves state of the art performance on the ICCV 2017 PoseTrack keypoint tracking challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning a Predictable and Generative Vector Representation for Objects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/2016_tl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/2016_tl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is a good vector representation of an object? We believe that it should be generative in 3D, in the sense that it can produce new 3D objects; as well as be predictable from 2D, in the sense that it can be perceived from 2D images. We propose a novel architecture, called the TL-embedding network, to learn an embedding space with these properties. The network consists of two components: (a) an autoencoder that ensures the representation is generative; and (b) a convolutional network that ensures the representation is predictable. This enables tackling a number of tasks including voxel prediction from 2D images and 3D model retrieval. Extensive experimental analysis demonstrates the usefulness and versatility of this embedding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
